<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-08-28T13:34:15+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Adam Dinan</title><subtitle>Postdoctoral researcher in bioinformatics and computational biology.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Shiny apps for exploring cystic fibrosis (CF) patient data</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2022/08/28/shiny-apps-for-exploring-cf-data.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shiny apps for exploring cystic fibrosis (CF) patient data" /><published>2022-08-28T13:25:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-08-28T13:25:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2022/08/28/shiny-apps-for-exploring-cf-data</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2022/08/28/shiny-apps-for-exploring-cf-data.html">&lt;p&gt;I have recently been working on a very exciting project in collaboration with Dr Odiri Eneje (Papworth Hospital) and Professor Andres Floto (University of Cambridge) as well as partners at GlaxoSmithKline and the University of Exeter, in which we are monitoring epigenetic status and gene expression in CF patient myeloid (immune) cells across a time series during a period of acute pulmonary exacerbation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will soon release a preprint of the results of this analysis, but in an effort to make these data more easily accessible, I have created two Shiny apps for exploring exploring gene expression in CF patients and matched healthy volunteers (HV). Simply type the name of a gene to see interactive expression profiles, or multiple gene names to perform automated clustering by group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These can be accessed at the below links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cf-varsity.shinyapps.io/neutrophils/&quot;&gt;Neutrophils&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cf-varsity.shinyapps.io/monocytes/&quot;&gt;Monocytes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">I have recently been working on a very exciting project in collaboration with Dr Odiri Eneje (Papworth Hospital) and Professor Andres Floto (University of Cambridge) as well as partners at GlaxoSmithKline and the University of Exeter, in which we are monitoring epigenetic status and gene expression in CF patient myeloid (immune) cells across a time series during a period of acute pulmonary exacerbation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to my personal blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2022/08/21/welcome-to-my-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my personal blog" /><published>2022-08-21T16:59:43+01:00</published><updated>2022-08-21T16:59:43+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2022/08/21/welcome-to-my-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2022/08/21/welcome-to-my-blog.html">&lt;p&gt;I am a Postdoctoral Research Associate in the Department of Medicine at the University of Cambridge and in the Laboratory of Molecular Biology, Cambridge. I am interested in the development and application of computational methods for functional genomic annotation using large scale data sets from bacteria, viruses, and humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I completed my PhD at University College Dublin, where I received a fellowship from the Wellcome Trust as part of the Computational Infection Biology programme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since graduating, I have worked with Professor Andrew Firth in the Department of Pathology, University of Cambridge, and more recently with Professor Andres Floto in the Laboratory of Molecular Biology and Department of Medicine, University of Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will use this space to discuss bioinformatics, data visualisation, machine learning, genomics, genetics and related topics. Please feel free to contact me if you would like to discuss anything further with me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">I am a Postdoctoral Research Associate in the Department of Medicine at the University of Cambridge and in the Laboratory of Molecular Biology, Cambridge. I am interested in the development and application of computational methods for functional genomic annotation using large scale data sets from bacteria, viruses, and humans.</summary></entry></feed>